Guide to the Lynne Tillman Papers 1939-2008 (Bulk 1984-2006) MSS 180 MSS 180
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XXI: Objects
  - Barbara Kruger, "Your body is a battleground. Support legal abortion, birth control, and Women's rights." T-shirt (Box 60, Object ID: 180.2.0013)
  - Barbara Kruger, "When I hear the word Culture I take out my checkbook" t-shirt (Box 60, Object ID: 180.2.0014)
  - Barbara Kruger, "I shop therefore I am" (Box 60, Object ID: 180.2.0015)
  - Barbara Kruger, "I can't look at you" T-shirt (Box 60, Object ID: 180.2.0016)
  - "Certain Radio Speeches of Ezra Pound" T-shirt. (Box 60, Object ID: 180.2.0017)
  - John Zorn Cobra T-Shirt (Box 61, Object ID: 180.2.0018)
  - Jazz trio T-Shirt, graphic by R. Lederman. (Box 61, Object ID: 180.2.0019)
  - "No Radio" Man with dog on bike T-shirt. J Humphrey graphic. (Box 61, Object ID: 180.2.0020)
  - Operation Minotaur T-shirt (Box 61, Object ID: 180.2.0021)
  - "No More nice Girls" T-shirt. (Box 62, Object ID: 180.2.0022)
  - "Sorry to be LIVING!!!" T-shirt (Box 62, Object ID: 180.2.0023)
  - "Caravaggio Film by Derek Jarman" T-shirt (Box 62, Object ID: 180.2.0024)
  - "Don't be afraid" project T-shirt (Box 63, Object ID: 180.2.0025)
  - "Don't give an inch" t-shirt (Box 63, Object ID; 180.2.0026)
  - "Screws" T-shirt (Box 63, Object ID: 180.2.0027)
  - Green headband with shamrock antena. Labeled, "Karen Finley World Tour 1990" (Box 63, Object ID: 180.2.0028)
  - Barbara Kruger "Don't be a jerk" bumper sticker. (Box 63, Object ID: 180.2.0029)
  - Barbara Kruger, "You are an experiment in terror" match books. 6 in celophane package. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0030)
  - Barbara Kruger, "Charisma is the perfume of your gods" match books. 6 in celophane package. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0031)
  - Barbara Kruger, "You construct intricate rituals which allow you to touch the skin of other men." 6 matchbooks in celephone package. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0032)
  - Barbara Kruger, "Your manias become science" matchbooks. 6 in celophane package. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0032)
  - "Cast in Doubt" rubber stamp. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0033)
  - "Cast In Doubt/Lynne Tillman" rubber stamp (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0034)
  - "Committed" rubber stamp (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0035)
  - Plaster dental model, top and bottom. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0036)
  - Plaster dental model of the right half of Lynne Tillman's mouth. Connected by a plastic hinge (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0037)
  - Plaster dental model, top and bottom (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0038)
  - Wrapped box tied with blue ribbon. Wax seals and pictures of urns decorate the outside. The inside is lined with blue satin and filled with tissue paper and confetti. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0039)
  - Bell and Howell electric eye, super 8 camera., Broken plastic frame surrounding the rotating lenses. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0040)
  - Framed photo collage by Tim Hailand. Inscribed "To Lynne Love - Tim (T. Hailand, 1991)" (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0041)
  - Drawing. Inscribed, "Deer Lin Merril love from Christopher" (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0042)
  - "I'll be the Judge. Women's Action Coalition" Black graphics on white cloth. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0043)
  - "Postes" woven plastic bag. (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0044)
  - Three small pieces of fabric (Box 64, Object ID: 180.2.0045)
- Oversize Series I: Correspondence
  Oversize Series I: Correspondence contains oversize materials from Series I.
  - Oversize I, Subseries A: Individuals and Institutions
    - Beard, Paul - card and sheet music, 1995-1996 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Blowdryer, Jennifer, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Grimson, Todd, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Stevenson, Harold, 2004 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Oversize I, Subseries D: Correspondence Files
    - Ford, Charles Henri, 1972-2003 (Box 41, Folder 5)
- Oversize Series II: Subject Files
  Oversize Series II: Subject Files contains oversize materials from Series II.
  - Oversize II, Subseries A: Artists
    - Albery, Nicholas - obituaries, 2001 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Angus, James, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Armstrong, David, 1993-1994 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Blake, Nayland, 1997-2003 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Blegvad, Peter - The Book of Leviathan, Undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Bowles, Jane and Paul - The Threepenny Review #21, 31, 1985-1987 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Bunn, David, Undated (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Cooper, Dennis, Undated (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Fish, Max - Drunk Driving Calendar, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Hawkins, Yolanda, Undated (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Hearn, Pat, 1995-2001 (Box 41, Folder 16)
      Removed from Box 10, Folder 43
    - Hofstra, Undated (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Hsieh, Tehching, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Kolbowski, Sylvia, Undated (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Minh-ha, Trinh - Critical Reflections in ArtForum, Undated (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Prina, Stephen, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Rosenberg, Aura, 2002 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Schumann, Christian, Undated (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Shore, Stephen, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Turyn, Anne, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Williams, Heathcote - Suck Solicitation, Undated (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Oversize II, Subseries B: Subjects
    - Collective for Living Cinema, Undated (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - DSM Categories and Description - News articles about schizophrenia, MPD, etc..., 1975-1989 (Box 41, Folder 28)
      Removed from Box 13, Folder 8
    - Guerilla Girls Newsletter, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - International - The Fanatic xeroxed Broadsheet Paper, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - Oversize II, Subseries C: Photographic Material and Miscellaneous
    - Family Portrait of Unknown Family - photographer: Shirlet Clarke, Austin TX, Undated (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - Fat City Cinema Club poster - Amsterdam, Undated (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - Feet: The Inside Story - with card "To Val, From Dee and All", Undated (Box 41, Folder 33)
    - Photograph of newspaper picture - girl, boy, and dog, Undated (Box 41, Folder 34)
    - Van Hensen Century Shirt Advertisement featuring Ronald Reagan, Undated (Box 41, Folder 35)
- Oversize Series IV: Committed (1984)
  Oversize Series IV: Committed contains oversize materials from Series IV.
  - Oversize IV, Subseries A: Drafts and Production
    - Frances Farmer Paperdoll - Zuilen, D., 1982 (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Oversize IV, Subseries B: Publicity and Distribution
    - Committed - Black and White photograph, Undated (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - Princeton - Women and Film Series, including Committed, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 38)
    - Village Voice - "The Price of Admission...", "Frances Farmer's Dark Victory...", 1982 (Box 41, Folder 39)
- Oversize Series V: Haunted Houses (1987)
  Oversize Series V: Haunted Houses contains oversize materials from Series V.
  - Oversize V, Subseries B: Publicity and Distribution
    - London - Promotional Poster for Haunted Houses, Undated (Box 41, Folder 40)
- Oversize Series VII: Cast in Doubt (1992)
  Oversize Series VII: Cast in Doubt contains oversize materials from Series VII.
  - Oversize VII, Subseries A: Drafts and Production
    - Cast in Doubt cover, Undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Cast in Doubt cover - color copy, Undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Oversize VII, Subseries B: Publicity and Distribution
    - Voice Literary Supplement - Reviews in Lit Hit, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 3)
- Oversize Series VIII: The Velvet Years (1995)
  Oversize Series VIII: The Velvet Years contains oversize materials from Series VIII.
  - Oversize VIII, Subseries A: Drafts and Production
    - Color copy of cover, Undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Galleys - before fifty images attached, Undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Paperback cover, Undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Photocopies of redesign, Undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Warhol File, Undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
- Oversize Series IX: No Lease on Life (1997)
  Oversize Series IX: No Lease on Life contains oversize materials from Series IX.
  - Oversize IX, Subseries A: Drafts and Production
    - Covers and Jackets, Undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
- Oversize Series X: Bookstore (1999)
  Oversize Series X: Bookstore contains oversize materials from Series X.
  - Oversize X, Subseries A: Drafts and Production
    - Photo proofs, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 10)
- Oversize Series XII: Essay and Story Collections
  Oversize Series XII: Essay and Story Collections contains oversize materials from Series XII.
  - Oversize XII, Subseries D: This is Not It (2002)
    - Juan Munoz - "This is Not It" for Parkett photos, Undated (Box 42, Folder 11)
- Oversize Series XIII: Other Works and Activities
  Oversize Series XIII: Other Works and Activities contains oversize materials from Series XIII.
  - Oversize XIII, Subseries A: Writing, Readings, and Artwork
    - Bomb - Lynne Tillman's "Cast in Doubt", 1992 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Bomb #57 - "Peter Dreher" by Lynne Tillman; #59 - "Kendall Thomas" by Lynne Tillman, 1996-1997 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Cinderella - Sketches, Undated (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Ideolects #9 and #10 - Cover mockup, Undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Lynne Tillman Reads in Brighton - poster, Undated (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Lynne Tillman - Wexner prize for Yvonne Rainer, 1995 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Paranoid's Annonymous Newsletter #1,2,3, 1976-1979 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - "Pleasure isn't a Pretty Picture" - Large black and white photograph, Aura Rosenberg, Undated (Box 42, Folder 19)
      Removed from Box 29, Folder 5
    - Published Pieces: Artpaper, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - Published Pieces - Bomb, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Published Pieces - A Vtre Extra, Fluxus, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Slant: Lynne Tillman on the Autobiography of Eve - Art Forum originals, April 1990 (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - Stockholder - Sketches, Undated (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - Voice Literary Supplement #105 - "A Dark Background" by Lynne Tillman, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - Word - "The Last Word", Lynne Tillman on "Exposures", 1995 (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Oversize XIII, Subseries B: Editing
    - Americans Abroad, Undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Americans Abroad - Mockup, Undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Craig Owens Project - Article masters, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Removed from Box 31, Folder 34
    - Exhibition poster for Roni Horn, Undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Guerilla Text galleys, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Oversize XIII, Subseries C: Publicity
    - Haunted Houses and Committed - event poster, Undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Patrick McGrath interviews Lynne Tillman for Bomb Magazine, 1991 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      Removed from Box 32, Folder 63
    - Stroemfeld/Roterstern Bag - Including Lynne Tillman's name, Undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Oversize XIII, Subseries D: Notes and Fragments
    - Dutch Film Maker's Coop amd Discussion of Films - including Lynne Tillman, Undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
- Oversize Series XIV: Education
  Oversize Series XIV: Education contains oversize materials from Series XIV.
  - Oversize XIV, Subseries A: Secondary and Undergraduate
    - Brighton Writer's Conference poster, Undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Feminism / Film / Looking - Readings, Undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
- Oversize Series XV: Printed Material
  Oversize Series XV: Printed Material contains oversize materials from Series XV.
  - Autonomedia Calendar, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Fandadangos, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - het Gewicht #3, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Illuminatus!, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Interview magazine - Andy Mania, 1996 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Life 55:22 - JFK Assasination, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Life 55:23 - JFK Funeral, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - See Magazine, 1948 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Straat #3, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Suck #1,2,3,7 - #1 used for Franklin Furnace exhibit, Undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Suck: Special Issue - The Virgin Sperm Dancer - Franklin Furnace Bookworks exhibition, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - a VTRE Extra #11, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Witch Craft in the Jordan, Undated (Box 44, Folder 13)
- Oversize Series XVI: Posters
  Scope and Content n
  Oversize Series XVI: Posters contains posters for conferences, film festivals, art shows, readings, etc.
  - AC/DC by Heathcote Williams, Undated (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 1)
  - Art Projekt '92, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Blueprint drawings for Lynne Tillman's Study, by Molly Hankowitz, Undated (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 3)
  - Bogosian - Sex, Drugs, Rock and Roll, Undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Charles Henri Ford - Printed Matter 1929-1969, 1999 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Christian Boltanski - "Lost: New York Projects", Undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Committed - Outstanding Film of the Year Award, London Film Festival, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Communism and the U.S.: History and Consequences, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    Removed from Series XIIIA, Box 25, Folder 25
  - Conference on Youth Music, Youth Culture, Undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Conference Posters - NYU "A to the K: New Directions in Popular Music", "La Guerre Indirect, En Direct", Princeton - "Sexuality and Space" (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 10)
  - Crime Calendar, Undated (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 11)
  - Critical Fiction - Dia Art Foundation, Undated (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 12)
  - Daniella Rossell - "Third World Blondes Have More Fun", 2002 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - David Salle, 1982 (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 14)
  - Event Posters and Container Notes, Undated (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 15)
  - Exotic Events - Times Square Show, Undated (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 16)
  - "The Fatted Calf" by Jeremy Sanford, Undated (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Franklin Furnace Fights for First Amendment Rights, 1990 (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 18)
  - Gregory Crewdson at Luhring Augustine, 2002 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Hallwalls - "Picture This: Films Chosen by Artists" including Specter of the Rose by Lynne Tillman, 1981 (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 20)
  - Haunted Houses - Poster from Barnes and Noble and container note, Undated (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 21)
  - Ink Painting, Undated (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Intercat '76 - The Bicentennial Cat Film Festival, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Jack Pierson, 1998 (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 24)
  - Jane Arden's "Vagina Rex and the Gas Oven", Undated (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 25)
  - Last Dance - Photographic Exhibition, 1986 (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 26)
  - Leven en Werk von Jane Bowles, Undated (Box 45, Folder 27)
  - Negotiations in the Contact Zone (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 28)
    Removed from Series XIII, Box 25, Folder 29
  - Palladium Exhibition, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 29)
  - Peter Cain at Matther Marks Gallery, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 30)
  - Poetry Project's Annual New Years Day Readings, including Lynne Tillman, 1996-2000 (Box 45, Folder 31)
  - Posters from book boxes, 1995 (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 32)
  - Princeton Architecture Lecture Series, 1995-1996 (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 33)
  - Reactions - Exit Art, Undated (Oversize mapcase 1E, Folder 34)
  - Re-Positions film program including "Committed", Undated (Box 45, Folder 35)
    Removed from Series IV B, Box 15, Folder 6
  - Sam Taylor-Wood - The Passion; Third Party, 2000-2002 (Map-case mapcase 1E, Folder 36)
  - "She Must Be Seeing Things" - a film by Sheila McLaughlin, Undated (Box 45, Folder 37)
  - Viewpoints - A Conference on Women, Culture, and Public Media, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 38)
    Removed from Series XIII A, Box 30, Folder 30
  - Williams, Heathcote - Elephants newspaper, Undated (Box 45, Folder 39)
  - Yasujiro Ozu - Anthology Film Archive, Undated (Box 45, Folder 40)